LLOYD ARMSTRONG

Infrastructure Solutions Professional

\ +49 174 5102923

@ lloydarmstrong@gmail.com

www.lloydarmstrong.dev

P Düsseldorf, Germany

@ linkedin.com/in/lloyd-armstrong

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Platform Engineer

Metro Markets GmbH

11/2023 - Present

□ Düsseldorf, Germany

- Designing, maintaining, and optimizing Apache data infrastructure for data collection, management, transformation, and access.
- Creating data pipelines using MySQL, Debezium, Flink and Kafka to manipulate raw data into usable formats for Business Intelligence Analyst and senior management to make critical business decisions efficiently.

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Metro Markets GmbH

- Reduced Google Cloud costs by 38%
- Refactored legacy Terraform & implemented customized modules
- Rightsized and refined resource use across multiple projects by using historical usage statistics collected using Grafana observability tools
- Implemented Helm deployments and introduce the use of Argo CD for
 Wilhernetes.
- Managed and streamlined GitLab CI/CD pipelines to reduce operational overhead

DevOps Automation Engineer

trivago - Marketing Solutions

- Lead embedded DevOps Engineer for 3 teams involved in Business Analytics and TV Advertising.
- Using the Hashicorp tech stack, migrated the entire Trivago Business
 Analytics platform from monolithic on-premise servers to a highly-available,
 local cloud, using Nomad, Vault, Consul, Levant and Vagrant.
- Reduced time to release by optimizing Jenkins CI/CD pipelines.

DevOps Engineer

Connect Mobile Communications

iii 09/2018 - 04/2020

■ Johannesburg, South Africa

- Migrated multiple monolithic server-based applications to a **Docker** containerized environment using Linux as our Base OS
- Built a Big Data platform from scratch using Elasticsearch and Logstash to process millions of data points daily, graphing in Kibana
- Implemented and managed Development, QA and Production Jenkins pipelines

Junior DevOps Engineer

Panoptix

- Hands-on startup role: Assembling, Installing and monitoring network analysis devices in secure banking environments.
- Contributed to building a custom application with ELK Stack and Saltstack Experience.

EDUCATION

B. Mus (Honours)

University of Chichester

2013 - 2016

SUMMARY

GCP and AWS Certified Engineer with 9 years experience in architecting, maintaining and growing cloud-based platforms and complex software development lifecycles. A musicianturned-tech aficionado, with a passion for automating things and new technologies that make our lives easier.

CERTIFICATION

AWS Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services

Cloud Architect Professional Certificate

Google Cloud Platform

SKILLS

| AWS | Google Cloud | | Terraform | |
|---------|-------------------|---------------|-----------|--------|
| Ansible | Kubernetes & Helm | | | Docker |
| Redis | Bash | ElasticSearch | | |
| Kafka | Flink | Gitlab CI/CD | | |
| Jenkins | Grafana My | | MySQL | |
| Prometh | neus P | ython | | |

ACHIEVEMENTS



Reduced Cloud Costs by 38%

Within 6 months of joining, I reduced cloud spend by more than a third!



Migrated from bare metal to Cloud

Started from scratch. No more server monkeys! We're in the cloud now!

PASSIONS

Producing Music

Aircraft and Flying

Gaming

Watching Sport